<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Royal Mabati - News</title>
  <updated>2024-07-26T10:59:55+03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Royal Mabati</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/kaa-chonjo-how-to-purchase-genuine-royal-mabati-products</id>
    <published>2024-07-26T10:59:55+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-26T15:18:47+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/kaa-chonjo-how-to-purchase-genuine-royal-mabati-products"/>
    <title>Kaa Chonjo! How to Purchase Genuine Royal Mabati Products</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[In the age of online shopping, it's tempting to jump at seemingly unbeatable deals, especially when working with a tight budget. <img data-mce-fragment="1" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/WhatsApp_Image_2024-07-26_at_10.54.24_AM_1_480x480.jpg?v=1721980671" data-mce-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/WhatsApp_Image_2024-07-26_at_10.54.24_AM_1_480x480.jpg?v=1721980671"><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/kaa-chonjo-how-to-purchase-genuine-royal-mabati-products">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>﻿</strong>﻿Consider this scenario: you see a Facebook ad for a cheaper roofing material. If you’re on a tight budget or planning to build your dream home, you might be tempted by the deal. However, many have fallen victim to non-existent deals, resulting in significant financial losses.</p>
<p>The rise of e-commerce has been both a blessing and a curse. While it offers the convenience of quickly receiving goods and saving on the cost of on-site shopping, it also carries the risk of receiving incorrect items or being scammed online.</p>
<p>The construction industry often faces high costs, which leads many to seek cheaper alternatives for sourcing materials. This trend includes shifting from on-site purchases to online ones. Royal Mabati has established itself as a trusted partner in construction through its direct purchase plan.</p>
<p>Based in Machakos, Royal Mabati has invested in a state-of-the-art laboratory over the past decade. This commitment to quality has resulted in roofing materials consistently meeting high standards, giving the brand a competitive edge.</p>
<p>Need roofing materials? Royal Mabati has streamlined its customer service, with technology and improved delivery systems ensuring that orders are fulfilled within 24 hours.</p>
<p><strong>To place an order for Royal Mabati iron sheets, trusses, or prefabricated house materials, visit our website at [www.royalmabati.com] (https://www.royalmabati.com) or download the Royal Mabati Ltd app from the Play Store or App Store. For inquiries, call +254722638383 or connect with us through our verified social media handles @RoyalMabatiLtd. </strong></p>
<p>Royal Mabati is committed to providing fast, high-quality, and genuine delivery of its products, with<strong> free delivery</strong> available to customers<strong> nationwide</strong></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img style="float: none;" alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/WhatsApp_Image_2024-07-26_at_3.13.50_PM_1_480x480.jpg?v=1721996282"></div>
<p><strong></strong>﻿</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/modern-construction-how-royal-mabati-saved-me-millions</id>
    <published>2024-07-26T10:26:48+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-07-26T10:26:48+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/modern-construction-how-royal-mabati-saved-me-millions"/>
    <title>Modern Construction: How Royal Mabati Saved Me Millions</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Construction often comes with a hefty price tag and long timelines, causing hesitation among prospective homeowners. However, affordable prefabricated building options are changing the game. Mr. Bramwel Omwenga, a retired teacher, chose Royal Mabati’s prefabricated home solution, completing his dream home in just 30 days. Prefabrication technology, praised for its cost-effectiveness and durability, is gaining traction in the construction industry. Discover how this innovative approach is making homeownership accessible to more people.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/modern-construction-how-royal-mabati-saved-me-millions">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When discussing construction, the first question that often arises is how many millions are required to complete the project. Construction has become a financial sinkhole for many, causing fear and hesitation among those who wish to build their own homes, worried about years of accumulating funds to finish their projects.</p>
<p>Traditional construction methods can be both cumbersome and costly. However, the advent of affordable prefabricated building options has transformed this narrative, making it possible for many to realize their dream homes.</p>
<p>Mr. Bramwel Omwenga, a retired teacher, is a prime example of someone who chose to invest his hard-earned money in a Royal Mabati prefabricated home instead of traditional construction. For him, the process was seamless and completed in just 30 days.</p>
<p>"<em><strong>You find that many people spend their entire careers struggling to complete their homes,</strong></em>" Mr Omwenga remarked as he received his prefabricated house.</p>
<p>Prefabrication technology represents a significant advancement. Royal Mabati, a leading player in the construction industry, has invested heavily in developing a client-focused approach that has resonated with many building enthusiasts.</p>
<p>The prefabrication technology, utilizing fibreglass, steel, and concrete, is praised for being both cost-effective and durable.</p>
<p>Tom, a building expert, highlighted that many contractors are adopting this new technology because it is environmentally friendly and reduces on-site accidents during construction. He also noted that the global market for prefabricated buildings is expected to be worth billions in the coming years, encouraging other industry players to invest in Royal Mabati’s innovative prefabricated housing solution</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/purchasing-mabati-online-tips-to-guide-you</id>
    <published>2024-06-16T22:10:28+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-16T22:10:56+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/purchasing-mabati-online-tips-to-guide-you"/>
    <title>Purchasing Mabati Online; Tips to Guide You</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div data-mce-fragment="1" itemprop="articleBody">
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Are you looking to buy roofing Mabati, and if yes, how do you ensure that you get the best Mabatis for your roofing needs? More importantly, how do you ensure that you get value for your money?</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Here are 4 simple tips to guide you when buying Mabati Online;</strong></b></p>
<ol data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1">Always conduct a quick background check of the Mabati factory before making payments.  Physical Location matters, you have nothing to lose by visiting the Mabati factory’s physical location before purchasing, Cheap is expensive; if the prices are too cheap to be true you need to think twice.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">Visiting the factory’s Facebook page and other social media platforms give a better idea of who you’re dealing with. Here at <a href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/" data-mce-fragment="1" data-mce-href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/">Royal Mabati Factory Ltd</a>, we pride ourselves on putting our customers first. We give you value for money and our Mabatis are durable, aesthetically appealing. <b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Here’s why you should consider purchasing your Mabatis online from Royal Mabati Ltd;</strong></b>
</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">     We have a clear and proven track record of delivering strong, durable and affordable Mabati</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="article-ratings-social-share d-flex justify-content-end" data-mce-fragment="1">
<div class="me-auto align-self-center" data-mce-fragment="1"></div>
<div data-mce-fragment="1">
<div class="article-social-share" data-mce-fragment="1">
<div class="social-share-icon" data-mce-fragment="1"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/risks-of-buying-mabatis-from-an-unknown-factory</id>
    <published>2024-06-16T22:07:03+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-16T22:07:55+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/risks-of-buying-mabatis-from-an-unknown-factory"/>
    <title>Risks Of Buying Mabatis from an Unknown Factory</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p data-mce-fragment="1">There are many Mabati companies that have come up over the last year or two. And while this is a good thing for Kenyan consumers, not every factory or brand is worth your hard-earned money.</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">What are the major risks of buying Mabatis from an unknown factory?</strong></b></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/risks-of-buying-mabatis-from-an-unknown-factory">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p data-mce-fragment="1"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/risk_480x480.jpg?v=1718564692" alt="" data-mce-fragment="1" data-mce-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/risk_480x480.jpg?v=1718564692">There are many Mabati companies that have come up over the last year or two. And while this is a good thing for Kenyan consumers, not every factory or brand is worth your hard-earned money.</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">What are the major risks of buying Mabatis from an unknown factory?</strong></b></p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">They include;</strong></b></p>
<ol data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Online scammers and cons</strong></b> are all over, <b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">ALWAYS</strong></b> think twice before buying Mabatis online.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Substandard goods</strong></b>; you also risk buying low-quality Mabatis that’ll start fading or leaking after a few months.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Unlicensed Mabatis</strong></b>; Some of these mushrooming Mabati factories haven’t fully complied with the Kenya Bureau of Standards. This means that the quality of the products you’re buying isn’t guaranteed.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Poor customer care services</strong></b>; poor customer services and low quality products go hand in hand. Avoid such by buying from a reputable Mabati factory.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">No warranty</strong></b>; what happens when the Mabatis you ordered get damaged or lost during delivery? It may not be easy claiming such when dealing with a little known brand. The beauty of dealing with an established brand is that your interests and satisfaction are always put at the front.</li>
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Special discount and offers</strong></b>; you’re more likely to enjoy major discounts and offers when you buy from an established Mabati brand. For instance, Royal Mabati Factory, one of the leading Mabati factories in Kenya has been offering special discounted prices and offers since mid-October; the special offers will apply all through the December festive season.</li>
</ol>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"> </p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">In a nutshell, conventional wisdom dictates that you’re much better buying your Mabatis from a <a href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/" data-mce-href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/" data-mce-fragment="1">reputable</a>, established Mabati brand. It’s safer that way, plus you’re always assured 100% that you’ll get value for your money!</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Are you looking to buy Mabati online from a reputable, well-established brand? Then look no further, call Royal Mabati today on 0722 638 383</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/things-to-consider-before-starting-a-mjengo</id>
    <published>2024-06-16T22:06:32+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-16T22:08:19+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/things-to-consider-before-starting-a-mjengo"/>
    <title>Things to Consider Before Starting A Mjengo</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p data-mce-fragment="1"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/6_480x480.jpg?v=1718564260" alt="" data-mce-fragment="1" data-mce-src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0585/0457/7123/files/6_480x480.jpg?v=1718564260">Do you plan to start a Ka Mjengo soon? It could be a residential home, rental properties, a commercial building, you name it! </p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">If your answer is yes, then here are 4 things you should always consider;</p>
<ol data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Budget</strong></b>;</li>
</ol>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Obviously, budget is the most important consideration to make before starting a Mjengo. Get a professional to help you estimate the budget for each step of the Mjengo; the foundation, the actual building, roofing, plumbing, and electrical wiring, etc. Buying building materials like stones, sand, and Mabati mdogo mdogo can help you reduce the financial pressure.</p>
<ol start="2" data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Legal requirements</strong></b></li>
</ol>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Get proper permits and documentation from the authorities, depending on what you’re constructing. Nowadays, most County governments have Building and Construction departments that’ll guide you on what’s required of you. You may require special permits before cutting down some trees, changing a residential plot into a commercial one, and so on.</p>
<ol start="3" data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Season</strong></b>;</li>
</ol>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">With the heavy rains being experienced across the country, it’s very important that you get your timing right. Rainfall damages construction materials; it may even cause structural damages especially if you haven’t finished with the roofing. January to March are warm months, very ideal for starting your Mjengo. Between March and May, we usually experience heavy rainfall while October to December has short rains.</p>
<ol start="4" data-mce-fragment="1">
<li data-mce-fragment="1">
<b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">Safety</strong></b>;</li>
</ol>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Lastly, remember that cheap can be expensive. Never settle for inferior building materials in the name of trying to save money. You want a safe and durable structure, right? Thus, make sure that your Mjengo is done by a professional and that the materials used are of the highest quality possible.</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1">Here at <a href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/index.php/mabati" data-mce-href="https://www.royalmabati.co.ke/index.php/mabati" data-mce-fragment="1">Royal Mabati Factory Ltd</a>, we’re your caring and reliable partner during your Mjengo projects. We offer high quality and durable Mabati, at the best prices in the market.</p>
<p data-mce-fragment="1"><b data-mce-fragment="1"><strong data-mce-fragment="1">0722 638 383, call us now for all your roofing needs; we’re just a phone call away.</strong></b></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/five-modern-trends-in-roofing-enhancing-style-and-durability</id>
    <published>2024-06-12T12:35:01+03:00</published>
    <updated>2024-06-12T14:13:11+03:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.royalmabati.com/blogs/news/five-modern-trends-in-roofing-enhancing-style-and-durability"/>
    <title>Five Modern Trends in  Roofing: Enhancing Style and Durability</title>
    <author>
      <name>Royal Mabati</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[In today's architectural landscape, iron sheet roofing has evolved beyond mere functionality to become a statement of style and durability. As a leading manufacturer of iron sheets, we're excited to share with you the top five modern trends revolutionizing the roofing industry:<br data-mce-fragment="1"><br data-mce-fragment="1">1<strong>. Sustainable Materials</strong>: Embracing eco-friendly materials such as recycled steel or aluminum for iron sheet production reduces environmental impact while ensuring strength and longevity.<br data-mce-fragment="1"><br data-mce-fragment="1">2. <strong>Minimalist Designs</strong>:Clean lines, sleek profiles, and minimalist aesthetics are increasingly popular among homeowners and architects, offering a contemporary look without compromising on durability.<br data-mce-fragment="1"><br data-mce-fragment="1">3. <strong>Energy Efficiency:</strong> Integrating energy-efficient coatings and insulation technologies into iron sheets enhances thermal performance, reducing heating and cooling costs for homeowners.<br data-mce-fragment="1"><br data-mce-fragment="1">4. <strong>Customization Options:</strong> Advanced manufacturing techniques allow for a wide range of customization options, from color choices to panel sizes and textures, empowering home owners to express their unique style preferences.<br data-mce-fragment="1"><br data-mce-fragment="1">
<blockquote>
<h3><em><strong>At Royal Mabati, </strong>we're committed to staying at the forefront of innovation in iron sheet roofing, offering premium quality products that marry style with functionality. Join us as we redefine the future of roofing solutions.</em></h3>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
